<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 13:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Issues</title>
      <link>/making-requests/legal-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 13:46:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/legal-issues/</guid>
      <description>Here be dragons! If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure about a legal issues that comes up during your request, the best thing to do is contact an attorney. The OPRAmachine team consists of volunteers. We are unable to provide legal advice on specific requests. Only a licensed attorney can provide legal advice. OPRA caselaw reference information We are making the following summaries of holdings from precedential OPRA cases adjudicated in New Jersey courts available for requesters making use of OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>911 Tapes</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/911/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/911/</guid>
      <description>You can request 911 tapes under OPRA. Typically county sheriff&amp;rsquo;s departments or public safety departments would have custody of these recordings. For recordings of phone calls of municipal police departments, you should file your request with that department&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreement for Individuals</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/contributor-agreements/individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/contributor-agreements/individuals/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in contributing to OPRAmachine (&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Us&amp;rdquo;). This contributor agreement (&amp;ldquo;Agreement&amp;rdquo;) documents the rights granted by contributors to Us. To make this document effective, please sign it and send it to Us by email or electronic submission, following the instructions at . This is a legally binding document, so please read it carefully before agreeing to it. The Agreement may cover more than one software project managed by Us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agreement for Organizations</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/contributor-agreements/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/contributor-agreements/organization/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in contributing to OPRAmachine (&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Us&amp;rdquo;). This contributor agreement (&amp;ldquo;Agreement&amp;rdquo;) documents the rights granted by contributors to Us. To make this document effective, please sign it and send it to Us by email or electronic submission, following the instructions at . This is a legally binding document, so please read it carefully before agreeing to it. The Agreement may cover more than one software project managed by Us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attorney Bills</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/attorneybills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/attorneybills/</guid>
      <description>Warning: If you request several months worth of legal bills with detail billing, you may get hit with a &amp;ldquo;special service&amp;rdquo; fee for the labor required to make the redactions. Consider breaking requests for these records into smaller requests.
 Governments hire attorneys for all for all sorts of legal matters. In many instances, a local government may end up hiring several law firms, with each firm covering a certain area of expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch Requests</title>
      <link>/making-requests/batch-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/batch-requests/</guid>
      <description>A batch request is the same OPRA request submitted to multiple governmental agencies at the same time. An individual may wish to submit this sort of request if they were doing comparative research about the differences between municipalities or counties or even particular public bodies.
For example, a good use case of a batch request was this request for police use of force reports from multiple municipalities in Ocean County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>/making-requests/best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/best/</guid>
      <description>Keep your request concise and do not ramble / use the request letter as a venue to argue your opinion or your side of the argument of a legal case.
Be as specific as possible in your request. If you know what types of records the government agency may have that will answer your question, try and identify specific documents in your initial request and use narrow date ranges so your request clearly identifies the time period of records responsive to your request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Lists</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/bill-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/bill-lists/</guid>
      <description>Most municipal and county governments produce a monthly list of bills and claims. This bills and claims list shows the vendors and purchase orders open / processed for that time period. The report is generated by the government agency&amp;rsquo;s computerized accounting software and is sometimes included with meeting agenda handouts.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Cam Footage</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/bodycam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/bodycam/</guid>
      <description>Police body camera footage can be obtained under OPRA, however a special concern associated with it will inevitably be the large size of video files. For that reason, the video files produced by the body cameras are often too large to email. Police departments may request that you pay a fee to have the video burned onto a disc or loaded onto a USB flash drive. Keep this in mind when requesting body camera footage of specific incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budgets</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/budgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/budgets/</guid>
      <description>The Municipal Budget is perhaps the most requested municipal record, as it is passed every year and influences the size and scale of municipal government for the upcoming calendar, and for residents, that size and scale comes in the form of property taxes.
You can request copies of municipal budgets using OPRAmachine. Note that these budgets are commonly available on other internet websites.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAD Reports</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/cad-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/cad-reports/</guid>
      <description>Almost every police department currently makes use of a Computer Aided Dispatch (CAD) system. CAD allows police departments to effectively store data about calls for service and the status of officers in the field. It allows law enforcement officers to quickly obtain the information that they need to accomplish their jobs, as well as assisting dispatchers with the logistics of their operations.
Requesting CAD reports can allow you to get an idea of the types of police, fire &amp;amp; EMS calls for service at a given address for a period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>We have a code of conduct that governs user behavior on the OPRAmachine website, including the content of OPRA requests, annotations, and comment in our sponsored Facebook groups and pages. The purpose of this code of conduct is to maximize the ability of users to engage in a robust, wide open debate on matters of public concern, while also ensuring that the site administration can preserve the OPRAmachine community by creating a safe and harmonious environment for all users by equipping our administration team with the tools to moderate objectionable content that is contrary to the values expressed in this Code of Conduct or content that contravenes state and federal laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Bargaining Contracts</title>
      <link>/example-requests/contracts/collective-bargaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/contracts/collective-bargaining/</guid>
      <description>Collective bargaining contracts are executed with public bodies as a result of negotiations between representatives of the management of the public entity and the negotiations team of the union. Government employees are typically divided into collective bargaining units that negotiate contractual work and compensation terms for the employees that are covered by their respective union. The contractual agreements cover a range of items, from health and dental coverage, to work hours and the procedures in place for handling grievances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complaints</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/complaints/</guid>
      <description>The complaint is the first document that is filed in a lawsuit. It is a summary of the factual and legal allegations that give rise to the lawsuit.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:
https://opramachine.com/request/county_of_ocean_v_truex#incoming-1678
https://opramachine.com/request/elissetche_v_hatch_et_al</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information, such as social security numbers and dates of birth are disclosed by way of the government documents published in the course of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation. Generally, we will require a showing of material and substantial harm to an individual that would come as a result of the continued publication of information on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With Large Files</title>
      <link>/responding-to-requests/large-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/responding-to-requests/large-files/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the response to request will require a large amount of space, such as when videos are requested. There are several ways that custodians can deal with largeFiles when responding to requests through the OPRAmachine website.
Email Attachment File Size Limits Each new OPRA request submitted through OPRAmachine results in the generation of a unique @requests.opramachine.com email address. The requests.opramachine.com mail ServerIs currently configured to accept emailAttachmentsUp to 100 MB in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Department Policies &amp; SOPs</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/policies/</guid>
      <description>The policies and procedures that govern local and county police departments should be easily obtainable using OPRAmachine. As some of the example requests will show, it may be advisable to break your request into narrower requests to obtain specific policies in order to avoid dealing with special service charges levied by the departments due to the voluminous nature of the OPRA request.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Alerts</title>
      <link>/making-requests/tracking-requests/email-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/tracking-requests/email-alerts/</guid>
      <description>Our email alerts feature allows you to receive an email notification every time there is new activity related to the requests, public bodies or users that you follow on OPRAmachine. It is the simplest way to begin tracking OPRA requests. You can track requests made through the site without requiring you to publicly file requests under your real name, so if having your identity exposed is a concern preventing you from making a request, email alerts allow you to directly benefit from the information obtained by other people&amp;rsquo;s requests made on the OPRAmachine platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Bodies</title>
      <link>/example-requests/emails/bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/emails/bodies/</guid>
      <description>The bodies of email messages often reveal the most detail for a given piece of correspondence, yet getting them can often be difficult. In order to obtain the bodies of email, statutory and case law has required that requesters be specific as to the source of the emails (either sender of recipient), as well as the date range and subject matter.
Oftentimes, a strategy that can be employed by requesters to obtain the bodies of email messages would be to first file an OPRA request for copies of the email logs for a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account during the date range in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Delivery Issues</title>
      <link>/site-administration/technical-problems/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/technical-problems/email/</guid>
      <description>There continues to be problems with email delivery to a handful of municipalities. Their firewalls are improperly rejecting OPRAmachine correspondence. We need to investigate ways of approaching this issue and solving this problem proactively.
Spam Issues Identify towns where this is a problem
Amazon Issues We currently use Amazon SES to send outbound SMTP emails for OPRA requests sent via the site. We should investigate whether this is playing a role in deliverability and if alternatives may be warranted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Logs</title>
      <link>/example-requests/emails/email-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/emails/email-logs/</guid>
      <description>Since the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s holding in the case Paff v. Galloway Township, the public has been able to request fields of digital data, such as email logs.
Email logs consist of the metadata associated with a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account. They are almost like a snapshot of the account&amp;rsquo;s email inbox, as it reveals the sender, recipient, subject and timestamp of each email stored on the public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Verification</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</guid>
      <description>Before a user will be allowed to submit an OPRA request to a public authority, they will be required to provide a valid email address. The email address will be confirmed by way of a confirmation email. No OPRA requests will be sent until the email address is confirmed. The email address may be from any provider, including throwaway / Mailinator type services that allow an individual to anonymously register for an email account due to privacy concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How OPRAmachine Works</title>
      <link>/introduction/how-it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/how-it-works/</guid>
      <description>The following presentation shows how OPRAmachine works and explains some of the basic concepts about the site and its operations.
How OPRAmachine Works OPRAmachine is a statewide platform that is helping to make New Jersey government more transparent using the Open Public Records Act. - Send requests to state &amp;amp; local government - Track response time &amp;amp; publish responsive documents
Send Your Request  Draft request and pick which public authority you want to send it to Our software delivers requests to the email addresses of government agency&amp;rsquo;s records custodian OPRAmachine also takes care of tracking the timeline of the government&amp;rsquo;s response  Receiving Documents  OPRAmachine parses emails received from public authorities and notifies you when they respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Affairs Records</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/internal-affairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/internal-affairs/</guid>
      <description>The types of internal affairs records that the public can obtain under OPRA is limited to aggregate level summaries of cases that do not individually identify the officers that were involved in the case. Typically, the summary reports obtainable under OPRA will include a list of the types of cases and their disposition, such as whether the allegations were sustained or not.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON Data Feeds</title>
      <link>/making-requests/tracking-requests/using-data-feeds/json/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/tracking-requests/using-data-feeds/json/</guid>
      <description>You can get JSON-formatted data out of OPRAmachine by simply adding &amp;ldquo;.json&amp;rdquo; to the end of a URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Finance Board Case Rosters</title>
      <link>/example-requests/ethics/lfb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/ethics/lfb/</guid>
      <description>The state Local Finance Board holds jurisdiction over state ethics matters such as the filing of financial disclosure forms by local public officials. They maintain a roster in the form of an Excel spreadsheet that lists ethics cases against local public officials that are adjudicated by the board.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Papers</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/motions/</guid>
      <description>Motion papers are filed during the case and can take a variety of forms. The common thread of all motion papers is that they are requesting that the court do something, such as compel depositions, or a motion requesting that a lawsuit be dismissed.
Requesting motion documents can be useful if you are attempting to follow a case as it is making its way through the system, typically during the pretrial phase of the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Vehicle Accident Reports</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/mva-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/mva-reports/</guid>
      <description>Reports completed by police departments investigating motor vehicle accidents are obtainable under OPRA. Often, companies will file requests seeking copies of all motor vehicle accident reports for a given period of time. Police typically provide the reports in full, while redacting some sensitive personal information, such as drivers license numbers and insurance policy numbers.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pension Records</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/pensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/pensions/</guid>
      <description>The amount and types of pensions records maintained by local governments has varied based on the experiences of OPRAmachine users. Some towns provided pension information in response to requests, while others directed requesters to go to the State of New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s online pensions transparency center that allows individuals to lookup the details of state pensions.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officer Training Records</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/training-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/training-records/</guid>
      <description>You can request copies of police officer training and certification information for a given pollice department. There were several requests for these types of information that were filed by a user of OPRAmachine in 2017.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Speech</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/political-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/political-speech/</guid>
      <description>Requests made by individuals seeking to promote a particular agenda are permitted on OPRAmachine. We seek to serve all political stakeholders equally. We will allow all individuals of all political persuasions to use OPRAmachine to increase the public&amp;rsquo;s understanding of public affairs in New Jersey. To that, end we are providing a limited public forum for the purposes of a robust public debate on the matters of public concern that are uncovered by the various public documents that are regularly published on the OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Employee Salaries</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The Open Public Records Act provides that a requester can request that a governmental agency provide a list of all employees, including salary, job title, date of hire and reason for termination.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_50
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_87#outgoing-1833
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_30#incoming-1690
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_73#incoming-1683</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS Feeds</title>
      <link>/making-requests/tracking-requests/using-data-feeds/rss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/tracking-requests/using-data-feeds/rss/</guid>
      <description>You can use RSS feeds to obtain data on requests and responses sent via the OPRAmachine platform. On most URLs of the site, you can simply preface links with /feed/ in order to obtain an RSS feed for a particular public body, user or request.
Local news websites have incorporated the RSS feeds by allowing their readers to view requests for a given government, such as a county or municipal government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Moderation Principles</title>
      <link>/site-administration/reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/reactive/</guid>
      <description>To maximize the freedom of users to engage with our site, we moderate its content reactively. This means that we generally wait until an issue is brought to our attention to take action. Unless the user has continuously violated our policies after being given a warning, we are extremely hesitant to intervene, in the interest of allowing the users of our platform to freely express themselves. Members of the site administration team are expected to adhere to this principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Limits</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</guid>
      <description>By default, users of OPRAmachine are limited to 6 requests per day. This limit on the number of OPRA requests that may be submitted by user accounts is in place to ensure that users do not abuse OPRAmachine or send vexatious requests to public authorities.
We recognize that some users may need to make more than this amount of requests per day. Therefore, if you contact us and provide justification as to why you would like us to lift the limit, we will consider increasing the amount of requests you are allowed to send per day at our discretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Won&#39;t Show</title>
      <link>/site-administration/technical-problems/request-wont-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/technical-problems/request-wont-show/</guid>
      <description>One OPRA response simply will not show, no matter what we try and do. This is a mystery and we have not been sure how to proceed.
Upstream Github issue We have opened a Github issue with the open source software project that provides the code that runs on the OPRAmachine server. We are curently waiting to hear back as of 12/20/2017.
Full Error message A RuntimeError occurred in request#show:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding via Email</title>
      <link>/responding-to-requests/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/responding-to-requests/email/</guid>
      <description>Respond to request via email You can respond to an emailed OPRA request delivered via OPRAmachine just as if it is any other email. Simply reply to the email with a response providing the documents, seeking clarification or denying the request just as you would to any other email that you would receive from any other sender.
Please note that the characters that appear before @requests.opramachine.com in the email addresses that send requests are used by the OPRAmachine software to categorize &amp;amp; track OPRA requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding via the Web</title>
      <link>/responding-to-requests/direct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/responding-to-requests/direct/</guid>
      <description>If you would prefer to respond to an OPRAmachine request directly from your web browser, you can do so without having to bother with email. Please note that this method of responding will require you to register for an account with the OPRAmachine website using your government email address.
Responding using the web interface To respond to a request directly from the OPRAmachine website, simply navigate to the request webpage using a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Ethics Information</title>
      <link>/example-requests/ethics/schoolethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/ethics/schoolethics/</guid>
      <description>Before you file a request for records related to a school ethics matter, be sure to first check the website of the state School Ethics Commission. The commission regularly publishes PDF versions of their rulings in schools ethics complaints filed against school members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Crashes</title>
      <link>/site-administration/technical-problems/serverissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/technical-problems/serverissues/</guid>
      <description>The server that has been running the site has been crashing because of the high load due to user demand. We need to investigate ways to obtain better performance for the site or explore upgrades to the Linode instance.
Reasons for server crashes Since late October there have been a variety of reasons for server crashes at OPRAmachine.
Here are some of the reasons: - Lack of RAM - Database issues - Lack of disk space</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlement Agreements</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/settlements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/settlements/</guid>
      <description>When a lawsuit is settled against a public agency, the terms of the settlement are memorialized as a settlement agreement. The settlement agreement recites some basic facts about the procedural history of a lawsuit before outlining the terms of the settlement. Typically, the plaintiff (the person who filed the lawsuit) is paid a sum of money to withdraw their litigation without the public body admitting any liability.
Settlement agreements can be a useful tool for learning about the outcomes of litigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Leadership</title>
      <link>/site-administration/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/leadership/</guid>
      <description>The leadership team of OPRAmachine.com is responsible for making administration decisions for the site, such as implementing our content removal policy.
Gavin Rozzi Gavin Rozzi is the founder of OPRAmachine.com. He is responsible for managing most of the day-to-day technical issues that occur with the site and regularly fields inquiries from both users and governments on OPRA requests submitted through our system. He can be reached via phone at (732)-504-3636 or via the email link on this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/spam/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine team takes our responsibility to prevent our platform from propagating internet spam seriously. User accounts that post spam links in the comment section, annotations, requests or any other area of our web properties risk immediate suspension using OPRAmachine web services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Page Broken</title>
      <link>/site-administration/technical-problems/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/technical-problems/stats/</guid>
      <description>The statistics page is currently broken. We are investigating the cause of the problem
Github issue (Upstream) https://github.com/mysociety/alaveteli/issues/4433
Raw text of error message A Math::DomainError occurred in statistics#index:
Numerical argument is out of domain - &amp;ldquo;sqrt&amp;rdquo; lib/confidence_intervals.rb:28:in `sqrt&amp;rsquo;
Request:  URL : https://opramachine.com/statistics HTTP Method: GET IP address : 54.161.187.202 Parameters : {&amp;ldquo;controller&amp;rdquo;=&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;statistics&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo;=&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;index&amp;rdquo;} Timestamp : 2017-12-20 21:57:55 -0500 Server : opramachine.com Rails root : /var/www/opramachine.com/alaveteli Process: 23591  Session:  session id: [FILTERED] data: {&amp;ldquo;session_id&amp;rdquo;=&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;95647a59eaf52bc425f666123ae9fff8&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;locale&amp;rdquo;=&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;en&amp;rdquo;}  Environment:  GATEWAY_INTERFACE : CGI/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summonses &amp; Charging Documents</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/summonses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/summonses/</guid>
      <description>You can obtain copies of summonses for ordinance, municipal code or traffic violations issued by local police departments under OPRA. Be as specific as you can when describing the incident. Name the location, parties involved, and nature of the charges, if known in order to help the department identify and locate records that are responsive to your request.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Service</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/terms/</guid>
      <description>These are the official terms of service that govern your usage of the OPRAmachine website. Please read these terms carefully as you agree to them in consideration of making continued use of the OPRAmachine web application and affiliated online properties. These Terms of Service are the final agreement between you, registered user of OPRAmachine.com, and OPRAmachine.com (also referred to as “OPRAmachine.com,” “us” or “the site”). OPRAmachine.com is owned and operated by Rozzi Media Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Force Reports</title>
      <link>/example-requests/police-records/uof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/police-records/uof/</guid>
      <description>Police use of force reports can be a great tool for understanding the types of incidents occurring where members of law enforcement indicated that they used force in order to establish compliance.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:
https://opramachine.com/request/police_use_of_force_reports_janu_14#incoming-38
https://opramachine.com/request/use_of_force_reports
https://opramachine.com/request/different_police_department_annu_64#incoming-818</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Privacy</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/userprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/userprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine team is committed to maintaining the privacy of user email addresses. We will only use your email address to send you information about the OPRAmachine service, your requests
Any OPRAmachine administrator is strictly prohibited from publicly disclosing:
 Names of anonymous sources Private email addresses or (nonpublic) identities of anonymous account holders Hashed or plaintext passwords  A violation of this policy shall be cause for the immediate termination of any individuals associated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor History Reports</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</guid>
      <description>Vendor history reports are printed reports generated from the procurement software utilized by government agencies. The reports show all of the amounts and payments of money remitted to vendors and contractors paid with taxpayer money. They can be useful for documenting how much money has been paid to professional services vendors retained by governments at the state and local level.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vexatious Requests</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</guid>
      <description>Requests that are filed solely to harass governmental agencies (vexatious requests) are strictly prohibited and will not be tolerated on the OPRAmachine service. The OPRAmachine site administration does not condone the contents of any OPRA request.
The OPRAmachine site administration reserves the sole right to determine whether or not a request was vexatious, and we may wait to take action against a vexatious requester until the requester was provided an opportunity to be heard and / or an opportunity to correct or abate the vexatious requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/example-requests/social-media/policefb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/social-media/policefb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-18 Rozzi Media Group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>