<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch Requests</title>
      <link>/making-requests/batch-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/batch-requests/</guid>
      <description>A batch request is the same OPRA request submitted to multiple governmental agencies at the same time. An individual may wish to submit this sort of request if they were doing comparative research about the differences between municipalities or counties or even particular public bodies.
Due to spam concerns, the ability to submit batch requests is currently limited and requests to enable them are currently considered on a case-by-case basis. If you are interested in making use of batch requests, please contact us to discuss your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>/making-requests/best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/best/</guid>
      <description>Keep your request concise. Be as specific as possible. Try and identify specific documents and use narrow date ranges. This helps the custodian to quickly locate the public records that are responsive to your request, and helps you avoid being charged special service fees due to the time required to fulfill your request, such as if it is exceedingly voluminous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Lists</title>
      <link>/request-templates/financial-records/bill-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/financial-records/bill-lists/</guid>
      <description>Most municipal and county governments produce a monthly list of bills and claims. This bills and claims list shows the vendors and purchase orders open / processed for that time period. The report is generated by the government agency&amp;rsquo;s computerized accounting software and is sometimes included with meeting agenda handouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Cam Footage</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/bodycam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/bodycam/</guid>
      <description>Police body camera footage can be obtained under OPRA, however a special concern associated with it will inevitably be the large size of video files. For that reason, the video files produced by the body cameras are often too large to email. Police departments may request that you pay a fee to have the video burned onto a disc or loaded onto a USB flash drive. Keep this in mind when requesting body camera footage of specific incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAD Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/cad-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/cad-reports/</guid>
      <description>Almost every police department currently makes use of a Computer Aided Dispatch (CAD) system. CAD allows police departments to effectively store data about calls for service and the status of officers in the field. It allows law enforcement officers to quickly obtain the information that they need to accomplish their jobs, as well as assisting dispatchers with the logistics of their operations.
Requesting CAD reports can allow you to get an idea of the types of police, fire &amp;amp; EMS calls for service at a given address for a period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>We have a code of conduct that governs user behavior on the OPRAmachine website, including the content of OPRA requests, annotations, and comment in our sponsored Facebook groups and pages. The purpose of this code of conduct is to maximize the ability of users to engage in a robust, wide open debate on matters of public concern, while also ensuring that the site administration can preserve the OPRAmachine community by moderating content that is contrary to the values expressed in this Code of Conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Bargaining Contracts</title>
      <link>/request-templates/contracts/collective-bargaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/contracts/collective-bargaining/</guid>
      <description>Collective bargaining contracts are executed with public bodies as a result of negotiations between representatives of the management of the public entity and the negotiations team of the union. Government employees are typically divided into collective bargaining units that negotiate contractual work and compensation terms for the employees that are covered by their respective union. The contractual agreements cover a range of items, from health and dental coverage, to work hours and the procedures in place for handling grievances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complaints</title>
      <link>/request-templates/legal-documents/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/legal-documents/complaints/</guid>
      <description>The complaint is the first document that is filed in a lawsuit. It is a summary of the factual and legal allegations that give rise to the lawsuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information, such as social security numbers and dates of birth are disclosed by way of the government documents published in the course of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation. Generally, we will require a showing of material and substantial harm to an individual that would come as a result of the continued publication of information on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Bodies</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/bodies/</guid>
      <description>The bodies of email messages often reveal the most detail for a given piece of correspondence, yet getting them can often be difficult. In order to obtain the bodies of email, statutory and case law has required that requesters be specific as to the source of the emails (either sender of recipient), as well as the date range and subject matter.
Oftentimes, a strategy that can be employed by requesters to obtain the bodies of email messages would be to first file an OPRA request for copies of the email logs for a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account during the date range in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Logs</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/email-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/email-logs/</guid>
      <description>Since the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s holding in the case Paff v. Galloway Township, the public has been able to request fields of digital data, such as email logs.
Email logs consist of the metadata associated with a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account. They are almost like a snapshot of the account&amp;rsquo;s email inbox, as it reveals the sender, recipient, subject and timestamp of each email stored on the public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Verification</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</guid>
      <description>Before a user will be allowed to submit an OPRA request to a public authority, they will be required to provide a valid email address. The email address will be confirmed by way of a confirmation email. No OPRA requests will be sent until the email address is confirmed. The email address may be from any proider, including throwaway / mailinator type services.
This policy is in place so that we can represent to public authorities that the OPRA requests submitted through the OPRAmachine website are submitted by real persons and not computer spam programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Affairs Records</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/internal-affairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/internal-affairs/</guid>
      <description>The types of internal affairs records that the public can obtain under OPRA is limited to aggregate level summaries of cases that do not individually identify the officers that were involved in the case. Typically, the summary reports obtainable under OPRA will include a list of the types of cases and their disposition, such as whether the allegations were sustained or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Finance Board Case Rosters</title>
      <link>/request-templates/ethics/lfb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/ethics/lfb/</guid>
      <description>The state Local Finance Board holds jurisdiction over state ethics matters such as the filing of financial disclosure forms by local public officials. They maintain a roster in the form of an Excel spreadsheet that lists ethics cases against local public officials that are adjudicated by the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Papers</title>
      <link>/request-templates/legal-documents/motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/legal-documents/motions/</guid>
      <description>Motion papers are filed during the case and can take a variety of forms. The common thread of all motion papers is that they are requesting that the court do something, such as compel depositions, or a motion requesting that a lawsuit be dismissed.
Requesting motion documents can be useful if you are attempting to follow a case as it is making its way through the system, typically during the pretrial phase of the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Vehicle Accident Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/mva-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/mva-reports/</guid>
      <description>Reports completed by police departments investigating motor vehicle accidents are obtainable under OPRA. Often, companies will file requests seeking copies of all motor vehicle accident reports for a given period of time. Police typically provide the reports in full, while redacting some sensitive personal information, such as drivers license numbers and insurance policy numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pension Records</title>
      <link>/request-templates/financial-records/pensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/financial-records/pensions/</guid>
      <description>The amount and types of pensions records maintained by local governments has varied based on the experiences of OPRAmachine users. Some towns provided pension information in response to requests, while others directed requesters to go to the State of New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s online pensions transparency center that allows individuals to lookup the details of state pensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Employee Salaries</title>
      <link>/request-templates/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The Open Public Records Act provides that a requester can request that a governmental agency provide a list of all employees, including salary, job title, date of hire and reason for termination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Moderation Principles</title>
      <link>/site-administration/reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/reactive/</guid>
      <description>To maximize the freedom of users to engage with our site, we moderate its content reactively. This means that we generally wait until an issue is brought to our attention to take action. Members of the site administration team are expected to adhere to this principle. The goal of the site administration should be to only intervene in cases in which it is warranted, and get out of the way as much as possible in order to ensure a positive user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Limits</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</guid>
      <description>By default, users of OPRAmachine are limited to 6 requests per day. This limit on the number of OPRA requests that may be submitted by user accounts is in place to ensure that users do not abuse OPRAmachine or send vexatious requests to public authorities.
We recognize that some users may need to make more than this amount of requests per day. Therefore, if you contact us and provide justification as to why you would like us to lift the limit, we will consider increasing the amount of requests you are allowed to send per day at our discretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding via Email</title>
      <link>/responding-to-requests-records-custodians/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/responding-to-requests-records-custodians/email/</guid>
      <description>You can respond to an emailed OPRA request delivered via OPRAmachine just as if it is any other email. Simply reply to the email with a response providing the documents, seeking clarification or denying the request just as you would to any other email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding via the Web</title>
      <link>/responding-to-requests-records-custodians/direct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/responding-to-requests-records-custodians/direct/</guid>
      <description>If you would prefer to respond to an OPRAmachine request directly from your web browser, you can do so without having to bother with email. Please note that this method of responding will require you to register for an account with the OPRAmachine website using your government email address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Ethics Information</title>
      <link>/request-templates/ethics/schoolethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/ethics/schoolethics/</guid>
      <description>Before you file a request for records related to a school ethics matter, be sure to first check the website of the state School Ethics Commission. The commission regularly publishes PDF versions of their rulings in schools ethics complaints filed against school members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlement Agreements</title>
      <link>/request-templates/legal-documents/settlements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/legal-documents/settlements/</guid>
      <description>When a lawsuit is settled against a public agency, the terms of the settlement are memorialized as a settlement agreement. The settlement agreement recites some basic facts about the procedural history of a lawsuit before outlining the terms of the settlement. Typically, the plaintiff (the person who filed the lawsuit) is paid a sum of money to withdraw their litigation without the public body admitting any liability.
Settlement agreements can be a useful tool for learning about the outcomes of litigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Records You Can Request</title>
      <link>/making-requests/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/types/</guid>
      <description>The emails sent by public officials relating to government business, whether sent on their personal or official accounts, are obtainable by the public under OPRA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Force Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</guid>
      <description>Police use of force reports can be a great tool for understanding the types of incidents occurring where members of law enforcement indicated that they used force in order to establish compliance.
Example successful requests for use of force reports</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor History Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</guid>
      <description>Vendor history reports are printed reports generated from the procurement software utilized by government agencies. The reports show all of the amounts and payments of money remitted to vendors and contractors paid with taxpayer money. They can be useful for documenting how much money has been paid to professional services vendors retained by governments at the state and local level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vexatious Requests</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</guid>
      <description>Requests that are filed solely to harass governmental agencies (vexatious requests) are strictly prohibited and will not be tolerated on the OPRAmachine service. The OPRAmachine site administration does not condone the contents of any OPRA request.
The OPRAmachine site administration reserves the sole right to determine whether or not a request was vexatious, and we may wait to take action against a vexatious requester until the requester was provided an opportunity to be heard and / or an opportunity to correct or abate the vexatious requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-18 Rozzi Media Group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>