<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>/making-requests/best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/best/</guid>
      <description>Keep your request concise. Be as specific as possible. Try and identify specific documents and use narrow date ranges. This helps the custodian to quickly locate the public records that are responsive to your request, and helps you avoid being charged special service fees due to the time required to fulfill your request, such as if it is exceedingly voluminous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information, such as social security numbers and dates of birth are disclosed by way of the government documents published in the course of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation. Generally, we will require a showing of material and substantial harm to an individual that would come as a result of the continued publication of information on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Logs</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/emaillogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/emaillogs/</guid>
      <description>Since the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s holding in the case Paff v. Galloway Township, the public has been able to request fields of digital data, such as email logs.
Email logs consist of the metadata associated with a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account. They are almost like a snapshot of the account&amp;rsquo;s email inbox, as it reveals the sender, recipient, subject and timestamp of each email stored on the public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Moderation Principles</title>
      <link>/site-administration/reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/reactive/</guid>
      <description>To maximize the freedom of users to engage with our site, we moderate its content reactively. This means that we generally wait until an issue is brought to our attention to take action. Members of the site administration team are expected to adhere to this principle. The goal of the site administration should be to only intervene in cases in which it is warranted, and get out of the way as much as possible in order to ensure a positive user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Records You Can Request</title>
      <link>/making-requests/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/types/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Force Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</guid>
      <description>Police use of force reports can be
Example successful requests for use of force reports</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-18 Rozzi Media Group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/opra-request-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-request-templates/</guid>
      <description>We offer several different types of templates for requests on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>