<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>/making-requests/best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/best/</guid>
      <description>Keep your request concise. Be as specific as possible. Try and identify specific documents and use narrow date ranges. This helps the custodian to quickly locate the public records that are responsive to your request, and helps you avoid being charged special service fees due to the time required to fulfill your request, such as if it is exceedingly voluminous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAD Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/cad-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/cad-reports/</guid>
      <description>Almost every police department currently makes use of a Computer Aided Dispatch (CAD) system. CAD allows police departments to effectively store data about calls for service and the status of officers in the field. It allows law enforcement officers to quickly obtain the information that they need to accomplish their jobs, as well as assisting dispatchers with the logistics of their operations.
Requesting CAD reports can allow you to get an idea of the types of police, fire &amp;amp; EMS calls for service at a given address for a period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>We have a code of conduct that governs user behavior on the OPRAmachine website, including the content of OPRA requests, annotations, and comment in our sponsored Facebook groups and pages. The purpose of this code of conduct is to maximize the ability of users to engage in a robust, wide open debate on matters of public concern, while also ensuring that the site administration can preserve the OPRAmachine community by moderating content that is contrary to the values expressed in this Code of Conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information, such as social security numbers and dates of birth are disclosed by way of the government documents published in the course of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation. Generally, we will require a showing of material and substantial harm to an individual that would come as a result of the continued publication of information on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Bodies</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/bodies/</guid>
      <description>The bodies of email messages often reveal the most detail for a given piece of correspondence, yet getting them can often be difficult. In order to obtain the bodies of email, statutory and case law has required that requesters be specific as to the source of the emails (either sender of recipient), as well as the date range and subject matter.
Oftentimes, a strategy that can be employed by requesters to obtain the bodies of email messages would be to first file an OPRA request for copies of the email logs for a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account during the date range in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Logs</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/email-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/email-logs/</guid>
      <description>Since the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s holding in the case Paff v. Galloway Township, the public has been able to request fields of digital data, such as email logs.
Email logs consist of the metadata associated with a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account. They are almost like a snapshot of the account&amp;rsquo;s email inbox, as it reveals the sender, recipient, subject and timestamp of each email stored on the public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Verification</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</guid>
      <description>Before a user will be allowed to submit an OPRA request to a public authority, they will be required to provide a valid email address. The email address will be confirmed by way of a confirmation email. No OPRA requests will be sent until the email address is confirmed. The email address may be from any proider, including throwaway / mailinator type services.
This policy is in place so that we can represent to public authorities that the OPRA requests submitted through the OPRAmachine website are submitted by real persons and not computer spam programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor Vehicle Accident Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/mva-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/mva-reports/</guid>
      <description>Reports completed by police departments investigating motor vehicle accidents are obtainable under OPRA. Often, companies will file requests seeking copies of all motor vehicle accident reports for a given period of time. Police typically provide the reports in full, while redacting some sensitive personal information, such as drivers license numbers and insurance policy numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Moderation Principles</title>
      <link>/site-administration/reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-administration/reactive/</guid>
      <description>To maximize the freedom of users to engage with our site, we moderate its content reactively. This means that we generally wait until an issue is brought to our attention to take action. Members of the site administration team are expected to adhere to this principle. The goal of the site administration should be to only intervene in cases in which it is warranted, and get out of the way as much as possible in order to ensure a positive user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Limits</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</guid>
      <description>By default, users of OPRAmachine are limited to 6 requests per day. This limit on the number of OPRA requests that may be submitted by user accounts is in place to ensure that users do not abuse OPRAmachine or send vexatious requests to public authorities.
We recognize that some users may need to make more than this amount of requests per day. Therefore, if you contact us and provide justification as to why you would like us to lift the limit, we will consider increasing the amount of requests you are allowed to send per day at our discretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Records You Can Request</title>
      <link>/making-requests/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/making-requests/types/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Force Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</guid>
      <description>Police use of force reports can be a great tool for understanding the types of incidents occurring where members of law enforcement indicated that they used force in order to establish compliance.
Example successful requests for use of force reports</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor History Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</guid>
      <description>Vendor history reports are printed reports generated from the procurement software utilized by government agencies. The reports show all of the amounts and payments of money remitted to vendors and contractors paid with taxpayer money. They can be useful for documenting how much money has been paid to professional services vendors retained by governments at the state and local level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-18 Rozzi Media Group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>