<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRAmachine Docs on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information , such as social security numbers and dates of birth,
Remove of content is an extraordinary remedy. The OPRAmachine site administration intends for the site to further governmental transparency and openness. We believe that the transparency provided by the site, including the publication of request and responses provides a public service. We will therefore only remove content when exceedingly persuasive justification is provided that the content&amp;rsquo;s publication will directly and substantially injure a private citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Logs</title>
      <link>/request-templates/emails/emaillogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/emails/emaillogs/</guid>
      <description>Since the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s holding in the case Paff v. Galloway Township, the public has been able to request fields of digital data, such as email logs.
Email logs consist of the metadata associated with a public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account. They are almost like a snapshot of the account&amp;rsquo;s email inbox, as it reveals the sender, recipient, subject and timestamp of each email stored on the public employee&amp;rsquo;s email account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Force Reports</title>
      <link>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/request-templates/police-records/uof/</guid>
      <description>Police use of force reports can be
Example successful requests for use of force reports</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017-18 Rozzi Media Group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/opra-request-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-request-templates/</guid>
      <description>We offer several different types of templates for requests on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>