<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Apps</title>
      <link>/introduction/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 09:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/desktop/</guid>
      <description>OPRAmachine now has desktop applications available for Windows and Mac systems. The desktop applications provide the same functionality as the main OPRAmachine website in a new and convenient form factor.
We recommend downloading the desktop app if you frequently use OPRAmachine from your computer, as we plan to add more functionality in the future to make the experience more tailored to the needs of desktop users.
IMPORTANT NOTE: If you receive a notification the the app was blocked by Windows Defender Smart Screen (such as &amp;ldquo;Windows Protected Your PC) or if you receive a security warning from Google Chrome when downloading the app, you may safely disregard the warning and allow the installation to proceed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How OPRAmachine Works</title>
      <link>/introduction/how-it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/how-it-works/</guid>
      <description>The following presentation shows how OPRAmachine works and explains some of the basic concepts about the site and its operations.
How OPRAmachine Works OPRAmachine is a statewide platform that is helping to make New Jersey government more transparent using the Open Public Records Act. - Send requests to state &amp;amp; local government - Track response time &amp;amp; publish responsive documents
Send Your Request  Draft request and pick which public authority you want to send it to Our software delivers requests to the email addresses of government agency&amp;rsquo;s records custodian OPRAmachine also takes care of tracking the timeline of the government&amp;rsquo;s response  Receiving Documents  OPRAmachine parses emails received from public authorities and notifies you when they respond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>