<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRA Exemptions on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/opra-exemptions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRA Exemptions on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/opra-exemptions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory / Consultative / Deliberative</title>
      <link>/opra-exemptions/acd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 07:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-exemptions/acd/</guid>
      <description> What it covers: Draft documents created before final action of public agency.
Legal basis: N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1.1 exempts &amp;ldquo;Inter-agency or intra-agency advisory, cons ultative or deliberative material.&amp;rdquo;
See also: Legal cases involving the advisory / consultative / deliberative exemption
Example denials: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biotechnology Trade Secrets</title>
      <link>/opra-exemptions/biotech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 07:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-exemptions/biotech/</guid>
      <description> What it covers: Proprietary information about commercially used genetically modified organisms.
Legal basis: N.J.S.A 47:1A-1 defines biotechnology trade secrets as &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; any technique that uses living organisms, or parts of living organisms, to make or modify products, to improve plants or animals, or to develop micro-organisms for specific uses; including the industrial use of recombinant DNA, cell fusion, and novel bioprocessing techniques.&amp;rdquo;
Example denials: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criminal Invesitgatory Record</title>
      <link>/opra-exemptions/criminalinvestigatoryrecord/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 07:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-exemptions/criminalinvestigatoryrecord/</guid>
      <description>What it covers: Many police records, including those relative to investigations in progress and investigations that never resulted in a criminal prosecution.
Legal basis: N.J.S.A. 47:1A1-1.1 provides that a criminal investigatory record is “a record which is not required by law to be made, maintained or kept on file that is held by a law enforcement agency which pertains to any criminal investigation or related civil enforcement proceeding.” The same statutes also explicity indicates that criminal investigatory records are not &amp;ldquo;government records&amp;rdquo; within the definition of OPRA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislative Records</title>
      <link>/opra-exemptions/legislative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 07:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-exemptions/legislative/</guid>
      <description>What it covers: Materials sent or received by elected members of the New Jersey General Assembly and State Senate.
Legal basis: N.J.S.A 47:1A-1.1 exempts from disclosure:
&amp;ldquo;information received by a member of the Legislature from a constituent or information held by a member of the Legislature concerning a constituent, including but not limited to information in written form or contained in any e-mail or computer data base, or in any telephone record whatsoever, unless it is information the constituent is required by law to transmit; any memorandum, correspondence, notes, report or other communication prepared by, or for, the specific use of a member of the Legislature in the course of the member&amp;rsquo;s official duties, except that this provision shall not apply to an otherwise publicly-accessible report which is required by law to be submitted to the Legislature or its members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Examiner Records</title>
      <link>/opra-exemptions/medicalexaminer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 07:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opra-exemptions/medicalexaminer/</guid>
      <description>What it covers: Photos of dead bodies taken by medical examiners in the course of death investigations.
Legal basis: N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1.1 exempts from disclosure:
&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;any copy, reproduction or facsimile of any photograph, negative or print, including instant photographs and videotapes of the body, or any portion of the body, of a deceased person, taken by or for the medical examiner at the scene of death or in the course of a post mortem examination or autopsy made by or caused to be made by the medical examiner except: when used in a criminal action or proceeding in this State which relates to the death of that person, for the use as a court of this State permits, by order after good cause has been shown and after written notification of the request for the court order has been served at least five days before the order is made upon the county prosecutor for the county in which the post mortem examination or autopsy occurred, for use in the field of forensic pathology or for use in medical or scientific education or research, or for use by any law enforcement agency in this State or any other state or federal law enforcement agency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>