<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legal Documents on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legal Documents on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/example-requests/legal-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attorney Bills</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/attorneybills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/attorneybills/</guid>
      <description>Warning: If you request several months worth of legal bills with detail billing, you may get hit with a &amp;ldquo;special service&amp;rdquo; fee for the labor required to make the redactions. Consider breaking requests for these records into smaller requests.
 Governments hire attorneys for all for all sorts of legal matters. In many instances, a local government may end up hiring several law firms, with each firm covering a certain area of expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complaints</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/complaints/</guid>
      <description>The complaint is the first document that is filed in a lawsuit. It is a summary of the factual and legal allegations that give rise to the lawsuit.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:
https://opramachine.com/request/county_of_ocean_v_truex#incoming-1678
https://opramachine.com/request/elissetche_v_hatch_et_al</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Papers</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/motions/</guid>
      <description>Motion papers are filed during the case and can take a variety of forms. The common thread of all motion papers is that they are requesting that the court do something, such as compel depositions, or a motion requesting that a lawsuit be dismissed.
Requesting motion documents can be useful if you are attempting to follow a case as it is making its way through the system, typically during the pretrial phase of the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlement Agreements</title>
      <link>/example-requests/legal-documents/settlements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/legal-documents/settlements/</guid>
      <description>When a lawsuit is settled against a public agency, the terms of the settlement are memorialized as a settlement agreement. The settlement agreement recites some basic facts about the procedural history of a lawsuit before outlining the terms of the settlement. Typically, the plaintiff (the person who filed the lawsuit) is paid a sum of money to withdraw their litigation without the public body admitting any liability.
Settlement agreements can be a useful tool for learning about the outcomes of litigation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>