<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Site Policies and Procedures on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Site Policies and Procedures on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/site-policies-and-procedures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>We have a code of conduct that governs user behavior on the OPRAmachine website, including the content of OPRA requests, annotations, and comment in our sponsored Facebook groups and pages. The purpose of this code of conduct is to maximize the ability of users to engage in a robust, wide open debate on matters of public concern, while also ensuring that the site administration can preserve the OPRAmachine community by creating a safe and harmonious environment for all users by equipping our administration team with the tools to moderate objectionable content that is contrary to the values expressed in this Code of Conduct or content that contravenes state and federal laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Removal</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine site administration will endeavor to remove site content in legitimate instances where private identifying information, such as social security numbers and dates of birth are disclosed by way of the government documents published in the course of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation. Generally, we will require a showing of material and substantial harm to an individual that would come as a result of the continued publication of information on OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Verification</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/email-verification/</guid>
      <description>Before a user will be allowed to submit an OPRA request to a public authority, they will be required to provide a valid email address. The email address will be confirmed by way of a confirmation email. No OPRA requests will be sent until the email address is confirmed. The email address may be from any provider, including throwaway / Mailinator type services that allow an individual to anonymously register for an email account due to privacy concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Speech</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/political-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/political-speech/</guid>
      <description>Requests made by individuals seeking to promote a particular agenda are permitted on OPRAmachine. We seek to serve all political stakeholders equally. We will allow all individuals of all political persuasions to use OPRAmachine to increase the public&amp;rsquo;s understanding of public affairs in New Jersey. To that, end we are providing a limited public forum for the purposes of a robust public debate on the matters of public concern that are uncovered by the various public documents that are regularly published on the OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Limits</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/request-limits/</guid>
      <description>By default, users of OPRAmachine are limited to 6 requests per day. This limit on the number of OPRA requests that may be submitted by user accounts is in place to ensure that users do not abuse OPRAmachine or send vexatious requests to public authorities.
We recognize that some users may need to make more than this amount of requests per day. Therefore, if you contact us and provide justification as to why you would like us to lift the limit, we will consider increasing the amount of requests you are allowed to send per day at our discretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/spam/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine team takes our responsibility to prevent our platform from propagating internet spam seriously. User accounts that post spam links in the comment section, annotations, requests or any other area of our web properties risk immediate suspension using OPRAmachine web services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Service</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/terms/</guid>
      <description>These are the official terms of service that govern your usage of the OPRAmachine website. Please read these terms carefully as you agree to them in consideration of making continued use of the OPRAmachine web application and affiliated online properties. These Terms of Service are the final agreement between you, registered user of OPRAmachine.com, and OPRAmachine.com (also referred to as “OPRAmachine.com,” “us” or “the site”). OPRAmachine.com is owned and operated by Rozzi Media Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Privacy</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/userprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/userprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The OPRAmachine team is committed to maintaining the privacy of user email addresses. We will only use your email address to send you information about the OPRAmachine service, your requests
Any OPRAmachine administrator is strictly prohibited from publicly disclosing:
 Names of anonymous sources Private email addresses or (nonpublic) identities of anonymous account holders Hashed or plaintext passwords  A violation of this policy shall be cause for the immediate termination of any individuals associated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vexatious Requests</title>
      <link>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site-policies-and-procedures/vexatious/</guid>
      <description>Requests that are filed solely to harass governmental agencies (vexatious requests) are strictly prohibited and will not be tolerated on the OPRAmachine service. The OPRAmachine site administration does not condone the contents of any OPRA request.
The OPRAmachine site administration reserves the sole right to determine whether or not a request was vexatious, and we may wait to take action against a vexatious requester until the requester was provided an opportunity to be heard and / or an opportunity to correct or abate the vexatious requests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>