<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRA Request Examples on OPRAmachine Documentation</title>
    <link>/example-requests/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRA Request Examples on OPRAmachine Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/example-requests/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Lists</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/bill-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/bill-lists/</guid>
      <description>Most municipal and county governments produce a monthly list of bills and claims. This bills and claims list shows the vendors and purchase orders open / processed for that time period. The report is generated by the government agency&amp;rsquo;s computerized accounting software and is sometimes included with meeting agenda handouts.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budgets</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/budgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/budgets/</guid>
      <description>The Municipal Budget is perhaps the most requested municipal record, as it is passed every year and influences the size and scale of municipal government for the upcoming calendar, and for residents, that size and scale comes in the form of property taxes.
You can request copies of municipal budgets using OPRAmachine. Note that these budgets are commonly available on other internet websites.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pension Records</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/pensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/pensions/</guid>
      <description>The amount and types of pensions records maintained by local governments has varied based on the experiences of OPRAmachine users. Some towns provided pension information in response to requests, while others directed requesters to go to the State of New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s online pensions transparency center that allows individuals to lookup the details of state pensions.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Employee Salaries</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/public-employee-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The Open Public Records Act provides that a requester can request that a governmental agency provide a list of all employees, including salary, job title, date of hire and reason for termination.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_50
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_87#outgoing-1833
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_30#incoming-1690
https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_records_73#incoming-1683</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor History Reports</title>
      <link>/example-requests/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/example-requests/financial-records/vendor-history-reports/</guid>
      <description>Vendor history reports are printed reports generated from the procurement software utilized by government agencies. The reports show all of the amounts and payments of money remitted to vendors and contractors paid with taxpayer money. They can be useful for documenting how much money has been paid to professional services vendors retained by governments at the state and local level.
Example requests The following are example requests made for this type of record on OPRAmachine:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>